LAUREN SEERY-LOUDON

2/1 8 Clouston Court, Glasgow, G20 6AN | 07918 027624 | lauren.seery.loudon@hotmail.com

ABOUT ME

I am a studious 20 year old that is a 3rd year Scots Law and Politics student at the University of Glasgow. I am hardworking, dependable, organised and adaptable, all skills I have honed during my studies. Throughout my university education I have developed a firm grasp of research skills, strengthened my literacy, problem solving and teamwork.

In my spare time I am politically active; campaigning, along with debating and producing policy in my party's youth wing to go to party conferences. I have also been secretary for a society at my university of which I am responsible for the daily tasks to keep the society running, including admin such as emails and forms along with running the online engagement, publicity and arranging events/meetings. I am also a dog lover and quite the geek on anything I take an interest in. Through this I have also been able to develop my team work and leadership skills holding numerous positions.

Balancing my education, political activism and a part time job have proven me to be diligent, highly motivated along with excellent time management skills which allow me to complete tasks to a high standard within time frames whilst often under pressure from many directions.

EMPLOYMENT

University of Glasgow Widening Participation Team | Student Ambassador | 2018 - current

I work with the university's widening participation team on the Reach Programme and the Top Up programme for students looking to come to university along with the Local Student Orientation days. This involves doing talks with future students on what it's like to be at the University of Glasgow, what its like studying law and giving them tips and advice for applying and being at university. Through this I have gained skills in helping and teaching others along with confidence in public speaking.

VUE Cinemas | Customer Assistant | June 2019-August 2020

In my role as a customer assistant there is key focus on dealing with customer needs and maintaining good customer service no matter how busy or preoccupied in other tasks. This means knowing the current movies, our products and the legal rules in regards to movie screening and GDPR, meanwhile also completing roles to keep the cinema running smoothly with the constant deadline of the next film starting. Excellent communication skills are needed dealing with all types of requests by members of the public. Approachability and friendliness, along with ability to remain calm and rational during difficult situations is also needed as often customers may be unsatisfied. I am competent in stock takes and mechanising following plans from brands to promote their products.

Debenhams | Sales Assistant | Christmas periods (Sept – Feb) 2016 and 2017

In this customer facing role it was highly tailored towards customer service, understanding the wants and desires in order to provide them with the correct information to make a decision that best suits their needs. This role required exceptional communication skills to ensure that the customers received the key points along with ensuring customers felt satisfied with the service. In the demanding retail environment time is imperative, multitasking and having to meet deadlines constantly meanwhile also providing great customer service. In this role I was often helped out with merchandising and creating store layouts which

where eye-catching to customers and effectively showcased the products. Furthermore, I had to routinely organise stock and replenish it.

EDUCATION

University of Glasgow | 2018 – present | Scots Law and Politics Joint Honours LLB

St Thomas Aquinas RC Secondary School | 2012-2018 | Advanced Highers in Modern Studies and Music awarded BB. AAAABBC Highers in Modern Studies, Politics, Music, Geography, English, Mathematics and Physics awarded. AAAAAC awarded in National 5 English, Modern Studies, Geography, Physics, Musics and Maths.

My qualifications and current degree have required the need for excellent IT skills to produce course work and complete online tasks. I have developed adaptability with courses using different software and methods therefore having to learn quickly. Both my disciplines require the ability to research, analyse and think critically to problem solve with accurate information and authority.

WORK EXPERIENCE

RBS Legal First Steps Programme | 1 week

Through the RBS programme I gained great networking, communication and presentations skills that has helped boost my confidence for both my degree and job prospects. Learning the ability to talk to professionals to gain key information but also translate that information into a more digestible manner to be explained to those with less knowledge in particular fields. I also was able to enhance my public speaking skills in doing a presentation on a product we were to 'create', looking at advertising and also the legal implications, this helped my teamwork and leadership skills.

Ashurst | 1 week

At my time at Ashurst I was shadowing lawyers in various departments at the international firm. Helping with various daily tasks from admin such as drafting documents, writing emails and I also gained a greater understanding of commercial awareness and its importance in legal, political and economic circumstances. I also took part in workshops to hone skills for the legal career. Presented an end of week task regarding the firm and technological advances in the legal secto which was highly insightful as I look to be a lawyer in ever changing technological environments. The corporate international environment helped my understanding of commercial awareness and the importance of technology in the fast-paced legal environment.

Turcan Connell | 1 week

My experience at Turcan Connell was heavily client focused following a solicitor in a family law case. I shadowed phone calls in preparation for court hearings, went along to court with the solicitor and this experienced opened me up to the real hands on approach taken to get to the root of their needs and help support a client in difficult situations. I also got to visit with the property and wills department and shadowed the creation of legal documentation.

Sheriff Court and Prosecutor Fiscal Office | 1 week

In shadowing a prosecutor, though not such a hands on experience I had the unique opportunity to see the 'real people' side to the criminal justice system, further developing my drive to help others and building my

confidence in the sometimes harrowing environment. Opportunity to watch a case and its progress, along with discussion by the key players in the case - defence and prosecution - on its progress.

OTHER ACKNOWLEDGEMENTS

Political Experience | 2018 - present

Further than my university education in politics in my political activism I am constantly having to keep up with political environment at both UK and Scottish levels. I have been able to develop my communication skills towards often politically diverse and complex topics. During my time I have been elected into various positions, help run campaigns (albeit at the young wing level), developed policy and arranged events. From this I have developed my social media skills from promoting events to written statements and further membership engagement.

Other

- In my last year of Secondary School I was a Vice Captain, this leadership role taught me greatly the importance of team work and time management, working with my peers on organising events and bringing up issues without our school community.
- I am an ambassador for the Holocaust Educational Trust after doing the Lessons from Auschwitz Program.
- I am a participant in the SMF (Social Mobility Foundation) where I have taken part in employability workshops to further my skills for the workplace.
- I am a Robertson Trust Scholar, where I also take part in education and employability workshops.
- I took part in the Selwyn College Law residential at Cambridge University and was one of small amount invited for an interview and though I was not chosen to attend the university for my undergraduate degree this experience has taught me perseverance, and most importantly how to deal with pressure productively.